《神探飞机头2》
报告 目前不见踪影
Negative. No sign.
等等 我看到他了
Wait a second. I think I got him.
你可要知道 你能用那个东西弄掉别人的眼睛
You know… you could put someone's eye out with that thing.
王牌 乘客们都救上来了 我们要走了
We airlifted out the last passengers, Ace. We're heading out.
你们不管动物死活吗
What about the animal cargo?
别傻了 不过是浣熊 我若是你 才懒得管
Don't worry. It's just one little raccoon. If I were you, I'd turn back.
是吗
Yeah?
如果你是我的话 那我就是你
If you were me then I'd be you.
我会用你的身体在上面
And I'd use your body to get to the top!
你阻止不了我 不管你是谁
You can't stop me, no matter who you are!
废物！
Loser!
废…物…
L-o-o…s-e-r.
饿了吗 兄弟
Hungry, fella?
这样应该够阻止你一段时间了
That ought to hold you for a while.
别难过 史派克
That's okay, Spike.
我们尽力了
There's nothing more we can do.
你看 史派克
Look, Spike!
别紧张 小朋友
Do not fret, my woodland friend.
你的性命掌握在王牌威龙手里
Your life is in the hands of Ace Ventura…
别号宠物大侦探
Pet Detective.
不管发生什么事
Whatever you do…
绝对不要往下看
don't look down.
抓紧啊
Hang on!
抓紧啊 小兄弟
Hang on little buddy.
我抓住你了
I got you!
大概抓住你了
I think I got you!
也许没抓住 你在往下滑
Maybe not. You're slipping!
不要松手
Don't let go!
天啊
My goodness.
你好
Hello, heh.
我差点被你吓死
That was quite a shock.
很高兴见到你
It's, um, extremely nice to meet you.
我叫葛富顿
My name is Fulton Greenwall…
有没有人叫做威龙的
and I am looking for an Ace Ventura.
本寺修道者中
No man here…
没有人是这个
carries with him…
名字
a label.
什么
What?
哦 我懂了
Oh, yes.
隐姓埋名 早该想到
No names. How silly of me.
他是个老美
He's an American.
我们都是造物主共同的子民
We are all children…of the same life force.
当然当然
Yes, of course we are.
额
Well uh…
他有特异功能 会用屁股说话
He bends over and speaks from his rear.
哦 原来是他
Oh, him.
请随我来
Right this way.
他初来此时精神濒于崩溃
He came to us a broken man.
完全失去了生存的意志
He had lost the will to sustain his existence.
是的 我听说过浣熊的事了
Yes, I heard about that unfortunate accident with the raccoon.
这事件对他是大的打击
It was terrible for him.
但造物主
But the life force…
再度
once again…
垂幸降怜
smiled upon him.
他现在
He's now…
心灵恢复了祥和
at peace.
我在这里等着
I will wait here.
哦
Oh oh.
对不起啦
I must apologize.
算了 没关系
Quite. Well, uh, um, no harm done.
我先自我介绍
Let me introduce myself.
我叫葛富顿
My name is Fulton Greenwall,
现在我想借用阁下长才 协助寻找失踪动物
and I'm here to employ your services…in the retrieval of a lost animal now.
你能帮助我们吗
Can you help us?
你的要求会让我想到你的直肠
Your request is like your intestine.
奇臭难当 而且危险之至
Stinky and loaded with danger.
我们愿意重金礼聘
We can pay handsomely.
我现在是修道之人
I am now a child of light.
尘世富贵对我如浮云
Your earthly money holds no appeal to me.
两万块美金
Twenty thousand dollars.
咳-咳-咳-咳-咳
Re-eh-eh-eh-eh!
真的
Really?
不行
No.
我没办法
I cannot.
这里需要我
For I am sorely needed…
在这里
here…
静修
at the ashram.
抱歉 插个嘴
If I may interject?
最近寺里空间不大够
We're short of space.
而且你该善用你的天赋
And it's important for you to use your talents.
我帮你打包行李
Let me help you pack.
我还没达到天人合一的境界
But I am yet to attain omnipresent super-galactic oneness.
等着
Wait!
好了
There it is!
你天人合一了
You've just attained it.
真的
I have?
是的 就在这一刻
Yes. Just now.
你达到了
You are one.
你的眼神证明了一切
I can see it in your eyes.
你简直超级天人合一
You're more one than anyone.
修道成功的奖励呢
What about my medallion of spiritual accomplishment?
拿去吧
Take mine.
这是你八十年苦修换来的
This took you 80 years to achieve!
没关系反正我现在不想要了 真的
That's okay. I don't like it anymore. Really.
你是如此无私无我的奉献
In light of this personal sacrifice you've made…
令我不忍继续推辞
I have no choice…
我决定接了
but to take the case.
很好
Great.
我马上告诉大家
I'll tell the others.
师父
Master.
要好好地跟他们讲
Break it to them gently.
从没看过他们这么夸张
I've never seen them act like that before.
虽然难过 依然强颜欢笑
Denial can be an ugly thing.
该走了 飞机安排好了
We should go, Mr. Ventura. I've arranged a plane.
你先到下面等我
I'll meet you at the bottom.
我还要办一件很重要的事
There's still one more thing I must do before I go.
酷毙了吧
Isn't this incredible?
这下子肯定会作为一项记录的
It's going to be some kind of record!
每个人都喜欢苗条
Everyone loves a Slinky.
你一定要苗条
You gotta get a Slinky.
苗条 苗条
Slinky, Slinky.
加油 苗条 加油
Go Slinky go.
气死人 怎么有这种事
Oh, man!Can you believe it?
竟然就停在这里
It was right there!
再来一次好吗
One more time?
抱歉 我们快赶不上飞机了
Forgive me, but if we don't hurry, we might miss the plane.
说得也是
Of course.
我太自私了
How selfish of me.
走吧 我郑重宣告重出江湖
Let's do all the things that you want to do.
这是交配季节的中美洲麋鹿
Canadian moose during mating season.
接下来模仿的是
And now…
牦牛
a yak.
Yak.
花生吗
Peanut?
我这边有一个
Yes, I have one right here!
很大 不过我当它随身行
It's bulky, but I consider it a carryon.
要花生吗
Peanuts?
哦 原来如此
Oh, I see. Ha, ha!
我们谈正事吧
If we can get back to business, Mr. Ventura?
瓦察提部落向来爱好和平
The Wachati are a peaceful tribe.
由于族中圣物不见了
Since their sacred animal has vanished…
他们相信诅咒降临至全族
they believe that there is a curse fallen on their village.
发生于前一阵子 某个晚上
It all started some time ago when, one night…
因此 瓦察提长的女儿
So the daughter of the Wachati chief…
许配给瓦诸图族的王子了
is set to wed the first son of the Wachootoo tribe.
圣物将给公主做为嫁妆
And the sacred animal was offered as dowry for the marriage.
但是 若不及时找回圣物
But if it is not recovered…
结果将会造成
the result will be…
瓦察族大屠杀
the merciless slaughter of the Wachati.
威龙先生
Uh, Mr. Ventura?
飞机翅膀上
There's…
有人
someone on the wing.
有东西
Some…thing.
对不起 你刚刚说什么
I'm sorry, what were you saying?
瓦察提长的女儿
The daughter of the Wachati chief…
许配给
is set to wed…
瓦诸图族的王子了
the first son of the Wachootoo tribe.
太漂亮了
Spectacular!
充满了大自然之美
This land holds great beauty!
离犯罪现场还有多远
How far to the crime scene?
我要先带你先到树后面的
Well. I've been instructed to bring you to the consulate…
领事馆一趟
which is beyond the trees…
就在那片丛林的另一面 所以我们得绕过去 啊
on the other side of the jungle. So we'll have to circle around… Aah!
这方向盘有点松动
Steering's a bit loose!
该调整轮胎定位
Alignment's off!
威龙先生
Mr. Ventura!
领事馆到了
Ah, there's the consulate!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God!
看来我得找个停车位
If I can just find a parking spot…
我觉得我们应该开慢一点
Perhaps we should slow down just a teensy bit.
胡说八道
Nonsense, poopy pants!
我们速度太快了 真的啦
We're going a bit fast!
小心
Really! Look out!
停得恰恰好
Like a glove!
这车该送去洗了
You should get this baby detailed.
这是总领事的车
The Consul General's car.
跪下
Down!
That's it. Down.
好的 跪下
Okay. Down.
拜托
Come on, man!
哇
Whoa.
威龙先生 久仰久仰
Mr. Ventura, so looking forward to your arrival.
有趣 这样打马的屁股 好像也不太痛
Didn't seem that painful when you were doing it to the horse.
威龙先生与动物关系极密切
Ha, ha, uh, sir, uh, Mr. Ventura has an affinity for animals.
我们走走聊聊
Shall we?
没问题
Shalln't we?
告诉我 威龙先生
Tell me, Mr. Ventura…
你有多厉害
just how good are you?
你是工作狂
You're a workaholic.
你最近从北非的戈丹回来
You recently returned from a trip to Gotan in Northern Africa…
而且曾经跌个狗吃屎
and you just took a nasty spill because of some…
由于工地施工品质不良
shoddy masonry work.
厉害厉害
Very impressive.
告诉我你怎么知道吗
May I ask how?
没问题
Surely.
你手上磨痕显示你曾摔下来 高度约三至五英尺
The abrasion on your hand is the type sustained in a three-to-five feet fall.
鞋子上的泥灰显示 水泥工工作时漫不经心恶搞
The remnants of plaster on your shoe pointed to a careless mason.
至于你那只假表嘛
Your new watch, a quality forgery of Cartier, was…
八成是从北非黑市买来的
most likely purchased through the North African black market!
那我的工作态度呢
And my work habits?
工作狂
A workaholic.
因为你裤子上尿渍只有一小块
Urine stain on your pants…
显示上完厕所只抖一下
would signify that you're a single-shaker man.
太忙了 没空多抖几下
Far too busy for the follow-up jiggle.
佩服 令人五体投地
Brilliant, Mr. Ventura! Simply brilliant!
多谢过奖
Spank you! Spank you very much!
我们和原住民文化
We've been coexisting quite nicely with the native cultures…
和平共处两百年我们相处形同一家人
for the past 200 years. They're almost like family at this point.
- 是吗 - 当务之急是
- Are they? - It is imperative…
替他们寻回圣物
that we recover the sacred animal.
否则和平的瓦察提族将遭毁灭
If not, the peaceable Wachati will be obliterated.
瓦诸图族向来好战
The Wachootoo are bloodthirsty.
他们视圣物失踪为耻辱和诅咒
They consider its disappearance both an insult and a curse.
有东西塞住我牙缝吗
Do I have something in my teeth?
凯比
Ah, Cadby!
宴会很成功
Lovely brunch I must say.
奎恩来见见王牌威龙先生
Quinn! I'd like you to meet Ace Ventura.
这位是波顿奎恩先生 他是奎恩野生动物园的老板
This is Burton Quinn. He owns and operates Quinnland Safari Park.
请叫我奎恩
Most call me Quinn.
丁丁 说你好
Say hello, Tinky.
幸会 丁丁 所有鸟类中最聪明的一种
Pleasure, Tinky. Corvus corax. Common raven. Smartest of all birds.
濒临绝种
Rare in these parts.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
你的行头实在太惊人
That's quite a wrap you're wearing.
或许我可以再帮你弄点新鲜的
Perhaps I could get you some fluffy new slippers…
用无辜的手无寸铁的小海豹头皮做的
made from the heads of innocent and defenseless baby seals!
这个无赖是谁
Who is this ghastly man?
王牌威龙 别号宠物大侦探
Ace Ventura, pet detective.
阁下一定是「大富翁」游戏主角
You must be the Monopoly Guy!
谢谢你让我免费停车
Thanks for the free parking.
又是一个抗议份子
Another activist, Maguire.
抗议份子 没错
Activist, yes.
抗议分子 是的 呵呵
Activist yes heh heh.
威龙先生
Mr. Ventura…
享用大自然的恩赐没什么不对
there's nothing wrong with enjoying the fruits of nature.
或许你该试试
You should try it some time.
哦 好耶
Alrighty, then.
你知道吗
You know something?
你说得对极了
You're right.
「拘票 立刻坐牢」
"Do not pass go. Do not collect two hundred dollars."
的确不错 不过这太沉重了
It's lovely, but I fancy myself an autumn.
如果你玩够了 威龙先生
If you've quite finished, Mr. Ventura…
我们可以一起前往简报室
we might make for the projection room.
真烦人
Kookie.
这位是希杜 原住民保安队长
I'd like you to meet Hitu, chief of tribal security in the province.
请…
Please!
不要
Don't…
起来
get up.
目前为止没有任何线索
At this point, we don't have any leads…
不过类似情况 以前也有过
but we've had similar problems in the past.
哦
Oh heh.
对不起
Sorry.
这是麦德雷
This is Derrick McCane…
去年在本地区出现过数次
spotted several times in the province in the past year. He makes a living…
他专门猎捕濒临绝种野生动物
from rare and endangered species.
这两个是澳洲人
Ah, these two are Australians.
秃头的叫凯来克
The bald one is Mick Katie.
另一个听说是原住民抚养大的
The other is said to have been raised by aborigine.
原住民土人
Aborigines.
原住民都叫他
The natives call him…
叫他「卡吉」猎人的意思
Call him Gahjii the hunter.
这两人以盗猎闻名 有极大的嫌疑
Both are known poachers and have been seen in the area!
婚礼将在四天后举行 我不能坐视杀戮发生
This wedding's in four days. I cannot have bloodshed here!
一切全靠你了
We're counting on you!
知道了
Hi-ho, Silver!
出发
Away.
我让葛先生同行协助你
I've assigned Greenwall to assist you.
在你出发前 威龙先生
Before you go, Mr. Ventura…
我有东西让你欣赏一下
I'd like to show you something you may enjoy.
我俩都是动物爱好者
As one animal lover to another.
怎么了 威龙先生
Something wrong, Mr. Ventura?
没事 没事
Of course not.
真是个可爱的死亡之室
There is a lovely room of death.
好好保重 再见
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
坐下 象儿
Down, Boba!
你头壳坏了吗
Mr. Ventura, how could you?
王牌 部落村子就在一里外
Now, Mr. Ventura, I think the village is about a mile ahead.
太好了
Excellent.
爆胎啰
Flat tire.
老是这么疯癫癫 是吧
I think this joke has run its course, don't you?
当然
Certainly.
冒犯之处尚请见谅
I prostrate myself before you and beg forgiveness.
偶尔开开玩笑也不错啦
Don't get me wrong. I do enjoy the occasional prank.
我的脚跟走得好痛
It's just that my heel is getting rather raw.
我们爱你 黑暗大陆晚安
We love you, dark continent! Good night!
你听
Listen!
那是银背猩猩的叫声
The majestic song of the male silverback gorilla.
我们要赶快走了现在是交配期 它们充满敌意
We should move along. It's their mating season and they can get rather hostile.
哦
Oh.
对不起 威龙先生
Oh, excuse me, Mr. Ventura.
我要休息一下
I have to rest.
- 我看也是 - 哦
- Of course you do! - Oh.
瓦察提族相信他们的力量来源来自洞穴中
The Wachati believe they draw their power from these caves.
由于圣物蝙蝠失踪 他们陷入一片恐慌之中
Now they live in fear since their sacred bat has vanished.
蝙蝠
Bat?
你说什么 蝙蝠
What bat?
就是们此行要找的圣物呀
The one we're here to find, Mr. Ventura.
可是你没说那是蝙蝠
You didn't say anything about a bat.
- 那有何差别 - 有何差别
- What's the difference? - What's the difference, heh?
你见过蝙蝠吗 丑恶无比
Have you seen one? They're hideous.
目光阴森森的 脚带利爪巨大古怪的翅膀 尖牙利齿
Lifeless, beady eyes, clawed feet, huge grotesque wings. Even fangs.
还会传染狂犬病
They give you rabies.
说得没错
Yes, quite. I see your point.
你的意思是不接这案子
But are you saying that you won't take the case?
不 身为修道之人我对宇由生命充满了热爱
No. As a being of light, I must show compassion for all living things of nature.
很好
Good.
可是我绝不碰那东西
I'm not touching it, though!
我是说真的
No, spank you.
瓦察提族生性爱好和平
The Wachati are a peaceful people.
他们尊重所有生命
They find all forms of life sacred.
我喜欢上他们了
I like them already.
很高兴认识你
Nice to see you.
王牌威龙 别号物大侦探
Ace Ventura, pet detective.
今天下午怎么样
How are you this afternoon?
哦 好耶
Alrighty, then.
对不起
Excuse me.
你的蛋蛋露出来了
Your balls are showing.
千年来他们仍过着传统生活
They have lived in the same state for thousands of years.
在白人来此之前他们不知疾病为何物
They did not know about disease until the white man came.
他在耍什么宝
What's going on over here?
所有族内年轻战士必经过程
All young Wachati warriors must face five days…
五天的平衡考验和意志力训练
of balance and concentration.
要是不慎失足掉不来
Should he lose his focus and fall…
就得重头再来
he must start over again.
地震演习
Earthquake test!
他有一套
He's good.
经我琢磨他日必成大器
With my help, he could be the best.
该去见酋长了 威龙先生
We should see the chief, Mr. Ventura.
这边请
This way.
酋长说他知道你一定会来
The chief says he knew you would come.
酋长听不懂你在说什么
Uh, the chief has not understood the dialect you're using.
告诉他我很高兴见到他的圣物蝙蝠会及时寻回 请他安啦
Say I'm happy to meet him. And that his sacred…
蝙蝠
bat…
和发现时一样好
is as good as found.
天啊 酋长真的喜欢你
My goodness. The chief really seems to like you.
这是瓦察提族表达热情的方式
That is a great sign of affection in the Wachati tribe.
真的
Really!
这是酋长之子 欧达
Oh, this is the chief's son, Ouda.
传教士们教过他英文
The missionaries came through and taught him English.
我喜欢你
I like you!
乖乖
My…
我怎么那么红
Aren't I the popular one?
现在轮到我表示热情了
Allow me to display my affection.
现在我们真是水乳交融
It is the mucus…that binds us.
酋长说圣物供奉之处就在那边
The chief says that the sacred hut is over there.
小偷如何闪过守卫的
How'd they pass the guard?
可能是趁守卫打瞌睡时得手的
I'm afraid he was found shortly after…sleeping.
稍息 士兵
At ease, soldier.
「猴」非圣贤 谁能无过
We all make mistakes.
臭飞鼠竟住得这么气派
Quite an auspicious dwelling for a filthy, flying weasel.
威龙先生
Please, Mr. Ventura!
这是他们的圣地 只有他们族人才能进来
That is sacred ground. I'm sorry, but only the Wachati are allowed there.
轻松一点嘛
Take it easy.
我们吐过口水 记得吧
I'm the lougie guy, remember?
是的 是的 谢谢你 酋长
Eh, yes, yes, Chief. Thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
酋长说 除非及时在婚礼之前
The chief says that unless the sacred bat is returned…
找回圣物蝙蝠否则瓦察提族将有空前洗劫
before the marriage of the princess, the Wachati tribe will meet their death.
你说的是哪种蝙蝠
What type of bat are we talking about?
当然是那种大型白蝙蝠
The great white bat, of course.
克瑞普索拉种
Crepuscular Chiroptera?
是的 不过原住民称之为
Yes. But to the natives:
「史卡戈」
Shikaka.
史卡戈
「史卡沙」
Shikasha, ah!
「史芝戈巴」
Shish kebab.
「鲨鲨堡」
Shawshank Redemption.
「芝加哥」
Chicago!
你出局了
You're out of there!
快点 被淘汰了
Go on. You're gone. Go on!
你吃这个
Were you going to eat these?
王牌
Ace.
我要去查查那笼子
I've got to inspect that cage.
怪怪
My, my, my.
这水果盘真是好吃
This fruit paste is delicious!
陶碟子也很漂亮
The pottery is lovely!
用蝙蝠排泄物做的
It's made from guano.
排泄物
Guano?
这词我好像听过
That sounds so familiar.
就是蝙蝠大便啦
Bat droppings.
瓦察提族之为大自然资源他们用它制作很多器物
It's a chief resource of the Wachati. They use it to make things in the village.
太好吃了
Yummy!
这才是精采好戏 瓦察族伟大的传统舞蹈
Now, this is really fascinating. This is a great Wachati tradition.
处女的诱惑之舞
The virgin's dance of seduction.
我现在遁入空门了
I am now a holy man.
女人对我而言如同大地之母
I think of women only as mothers of our children.
她们是生命繁衍的圣殿
They are a sanctuary for the reproductive organs.
人类生生不息的神圣象征
A temple to house the miracle of procreation.
一块钱借我当小费
Do you have $1?
谢了 我好多年不跳舞啰
Thank you so much! I've not danced in years!
嗨
Hi.
别管我
Don't mind me.
乖乖睡吧
Sleep.
快睡吧
Sleep!
我闻到了指纹的气息
I smell the fingerprints of scum.
我得进行指纹采样
Better dust the place.
一干二净
Totally clean.
什么线索也没有
Not one damn clue.
除非这是
Unless…
她过来了 不妙
Here she comes. Oh, boy.
我是圣人 我是圣人
Holy, holy, holy, holy.
心如明镜 莫惹尘埃
Good thoughts in, bad thoughts out.
承蒙你挺身相助
You have come to help us.
我们非常感激你的大恩大德
We are in…great appreciation.
你
You…
会讲英文
speak English.
是的
Yes, heh!
- 传教士教我的 - 哦
- The missionaries came with books. - Oh.
你不赖嘛
You are very good with that, heh!
精确无比
It's incredibly accurate.
要不要试试
Care to try?
不错嘛
Not bad!
再来一次 肩膀放松
Try again. Relax your shoulders.
吸气
Breathe.
再吐气
And release.
就是这样
There you go!
你逗得我好开心
You make me smile.
但是
And yet…
我的麻烦仍未解决
I am troubled.
你知道吗
You see…
我爸爸要我嫁的人
the man my father wants me to marry…
我担心不知如何取悦他
I am worried I will not please him.
我
I…
我从没有接触过男人
I've never known a man.
我很愿意帮你忙
I'd love to help.
可是你知道
But you see…
终身要做苦行僧侣
I have vowed to take a life of celibacy.
既然如此
Well…
或许这个
Perhaps this…
可以让你下定决心
will assist your decision.
它们是很诱人
Those are very nice.
不过我是修道之人 心如止水
But I am a child of light. A pure spirit.
美色对我毫无影响
I'm no longer encumbered by sexual appetites.
我的妈呀
Oh, mama, oh, mama, oh, mama, oh, mama…
对不起 打扰了
I'm so sorry, Mr. Ventura…
没关系
That's okay.
我刚刚在
I was just…
练习念咒
practicing my mantra.
哦 额
Oh uh…
- 你不是说要去洞穴中看看 - 是呀
- You wanted to visit the sacred caves. - I do!
- 到外面等我十分钟 - 嗯
- Meet me outside in 10 minutes. - Mm-hm.
让我继续完成冥想
If I don't finish my meditation…
否则我会心神不宁
I tend to get a little cranky.
保重 再见
Take care, now. Bye-bye, then.
似是柳暗花明又一「洞」
Everything here seems good! Heh, big load off my mind!
俗话说得好 不入虎穴焉得虎子
You can speculate all you want, but unless you check it out yourself…
不试你永远不会知道 我们回去吧
you never know. Let's go back.
你不进去看看
Don't you think you should investigate?
没有这个必要
There's no reason to go in there. Ever.
凭我圣人的直觉
I sense it as a holy man.
- 你说你要 - 里面黑漆漆的
- You said you wanted… - It's dark!
我会跌得狗吃屎
I could fall into a precipice.
这个借你
Take this.
谢了 你可真会帮忙
Spank you, Helpy Helperton.
不怕
I am not afraid!
我不怕
I am not afraid.
我喜欢这里
I really like it here, oh.
我的护身符
My medallion!
只要有了这个
I will fear no living creature…
我不怕任何妖魔鬼怪
as long as I keep this near me.
吃我一记 你这妖魔
Take that, you winged spawn of Satan!
没关系 不怕
That's okay.
还有火把在手上
All I really need is my torch.
去死吧 你这妖鸟
Die, devil bird! Aah!
没事没事
I'm okay.
跑到我头发里面了啦在我的头发里面啦
They're in my hair! They're in my hair!
天啊 快救我
God in heaven! Help me!
王牌
Ace.
你头发里没有东西
There is nothing in your hair.
说的也是
Exactly.
我是在测验你们的警觉性如何
I was merely running a drill.
一切正如我怀疑
Just as I suspected.
- 奎恩来过这洞穴 - 什么
- Quinn. - What?
我们在凯比宴会上见过他
We met him at Cadby's soiree.
他带着一只鸟鸦丁丁
His bird is a raven, Tinky. I found that inside the cave.
我在洞中找到它羽毛 奎恩这个人势力庞大
You don't understand. Burton Quinn is a powerful man.
别担心
Worry not, my brother.
因为
For I…
我是个化妆
am a master…
大师
of disguises.
兄弟们 尽量吃吧
Eat up, guys!
千万别浪费食物
None of this animal goes to waste.
麦先生 你好吗
Ah.
麦德雷 先生
Mr. McCane.
最近怎么样
How're you?
马马虎虎啦
I'm doing well.
奎恩先生 不用管我
Unh. Don't mind me, Mr. Quinn.
我的小犀牛会自得其乐
I'm just a curious little rhino.
你能答应
I appreciate your…
我十分感激
agreeing to undertake this.
竟和死徒在此碰头
Meeting secretly with sinister types much?
两人在搞什秘密飞机
Ah, not too much. Ah, much too much.
在犀牛肚子里可真热
Kind of hot in these rhinos.
热死我了
Warm!
我有一条狗 他的名字是
I had a dog and his name was…
冰果
Bingo.
我需要一点新鲜空气
Ah, time to get some oxygen.
不妙
Come on!
谁来救我
Mayday!
我 要 空气
Must have air!
快来
Come on! girls.
安静 你们快过来看
Quiet, quiet, quiet. Look, look.
你们看
Oh, look!
母犀牛在生小犀牛
The mother rhino is giving birth.
天啊
Oh, God.
妈咪
Mommy!
太酷了
Cool!
我们得离开这
We have to get out of here!
快点 快上车
Quick, get in the jeep.
快点 姑娘们 进去
Quick. girls. get in.
欢迎光临奎恩动物园
Welcome to Quinnland.
你也是 我的老友
And you too, my friend.
你会感到宾至如归
I know you'll be happy here.
哼 啊
Huh. Ah.
你怎么溜出来 小朋友
How did you get out, fella?
你这个坏东西
You're a cute little devil.
你拿的是什么
What you got?
蝙蝠在哪里
Where's the bat?
这是干什么
What's this about?
你是谁
Who are you?
蝙蝠
Where…
在
is…
哪里
the bat?
我想起来你是谁了
I know who you are.
我们在凯比家见过
I met you at Cadby's!
你就是
You're that…
威龙
Ventura fella.
最后一次机会
Last chance!
蝙蝠到底在哪里
Where is that darn bat?
你想干什么 你要怎么样
What're you going to do? What're you going to do?
我会让你招出来的
Whatever I have to get some answers.
停
Stop!
停下来
Stop it!
你要我停下来吗
You'd like me to stop it, hmm?
这声音好听吗
Getting to you?
我什么也不会告诉你
Ah, I won't tell you anything.
呜
Ooh.
你爱充英雄 是吗
A tough guy, huh?
我知道怎么对待英雄
I know what to do with tough guys.
我哥哥最喜欢跟我来这一招
My brother used to do that to me!
你这个变态的混蛋 住手
You sadistic bastard!
停下来
Stop it!
好吧 我老实招
All right! I'll talk!
- 快说 - 我付钱给 麦德雷 请他找那蝙蝠
- Spill it! - I paid Derrick McCane to find the bat.
以便吸引观光客来
I thought it could be an attraction.
这阵子生意不大好
Business has been a bit off lately.
所以
So…
你也不知道
you don't know who…
- 蝙蝠的下落 - 麦德雷 也不知道
- took the bat? - Neither does McCane.
好
Okay.
我这就放了你
I'm going to untie you now.
希望你了解 我是真的
Before I do, I want you to know that I'm really…
感到
truly…
非常
very…
抱歉
sorry.
谢谢你让我搭便车
Appreciate the lift!
我们会自己走回去
We'll walk from here.
奎恩没有嫌疑 这下子线索又断了
Quinn is out of the picture. We have no more suspects or clues.
不过我有第六感
But I have instincts back.
直觉告诉我就快找到嫌犯
And my instincts tell me we're getting closer.
我感觉得出来
I can feel it.
我感觉到了 就在
I can feel it like it's right…
我的脖子上
in my neck!
快跑
Run!
脖子开始麻了
Starting to get numb!
中了三箭
Three darts…
好像太多啰
is too much.
大概躲过了
I think I lost them!
这花是给我的花吗
Flowers…for me?
白瑞德先生
I do declare, Mr. Beauregard.
你是我的英雄
You are my hero.
我有
Was I…
说梦话吗
talking in my sleep?
你一直处于歇斯底里状态
You've been suffering hysteria.
典型的中毒后自然反应
It's a natural reaction to the poison in these darts.
喝点水
Water.
排泄物做的碗
Guano bowls.
刚好可以配一套
Collect the whole set.
王牌 你看楚是谁偷袭的吗
Ace, did you see the shooter?
只看到脚
Only their feet.
证据不足
Not enough for a positive ID.
这是瓦诸巫师的毒箭
It's the dart of a Wachootoo shaman.
你说什么
The what-y what-an?
瓦诸图族的巫师他对落这次通婚极为反对
The Wachootoo shaman, or medicine man, protests the intertribal wedding.
是吗
Does he?
你不会说瓦诸图语
You do not speak Wachootoo.
我和你一起去
I go with you.
欧达会替我翻译
Ouda will be my interpreter.
王牌
Ace.
你要小心一点
Please, take care.
他们是野蛮人 落到他们手你会凶多吉少
The Wachootoo are savages. If they catch you, they'll be merciless.
不要担心 兄弟
Worry not that brother.
我将会是墙上的一只苍蝇 海里的一粒盐
I will be as a fly on the wall. a grain of salt in the ocean.
我将会穿梭在他们中间 犹如透明的
I will slip amongst them like a transparent…
东西
thing.
蝙蝠一定在那茅屋里
The sacred bat must be in a hut.
我得想法子混进去
We'll never know until I can walk freely among them.
太好了
Wunderbar!
我有个绝好的点子
He exclaimed with great relish.
快点 女孩们 加油
Come on, girls, show them what you got. Unh!
非常好
Big finish.
没关系 我不怕
I'm sure it's fine.
欧达应该会带救兵来
Ouda is probably going for help right now.
你好 王牌
Hello, Ace!
他们逮到我了 不用担心
They found me! No sweat!
也不用自责
Don't beat yourself up.
你知道吗
You know…
口香糖是引起蛀牙最主要原因
gingivitis is the number one cause of all tooth decay.
「依昆苏欧查」是什么意思
What does "equinsu ocha" mean?
白色的魔鬼
White devil.
- 告诉他我不是 - 我刚认识你 怎知你是不是
- Tell him I'm not. - I only met you. How do I know?
- 他说 - 我猜猜看「白色魔鬼」吗
- He said… - Let me guess."White devil"?
答对了 你会瓦诸图语
Yes. You speak Wachootoo?
你替我翻译
Tell them what I'm saying:
我为了和平前来此地
I come in peace!
我听到你说「依昆苏欧查」
I couldn't help but notice the "equinsu ocha" part.
连你也说我是白色魔鬼
Did you refer to me as "White Devil"?
他们说你是 你就是
That's how they know you.
先撇开这话题
Leave that part out from now on.
我代表公主前来
I represent the princess!
战争如同地狱般
War is hell.
我们绝不愿轻易
The last thing we want…
开战
is a fight.
酋长说
The chief said…
若你通过他们的考验
if you pass all Wachootoo tests…
就饶你不死
you do not die.
真烦
Kookie.
我终于进入了决赛圈
Ah. My entrance to the winner's circle!
我知道我赢得各位尊敬但我不过是个小人物
Your admiration is well-founded, but I'm merely a servant.
千万别太崇拜我
Do not worship me!
酋长说这是最后一关
Chief says you have passed all tests but one.
瓦诸图的死亡决赛圈
Only left is Wachootoo Circle of Death.
有趣
Funny…
这个我最厉害
that's my specialty.
就是这傢伙
This is it?
我要打败他
I have to beat him?
哦 好耶
Alrighty, then!
我必须告诉你
I must tell you…
其实我一点也不想打架
I don't wish to fight you.
现在的我不再滥用暴力
Violence is no longer in my nature…
不过若你坚持 我也奉陪
but if you want it, you got it, sister.
你在咬我
Biting, I see.
我倒还不知道瓦诸图族
I was unaware that the Wachootoo…
竟会乱咬人
were biters!
不怕死就再试试看
Why don't you try this on and see how it fits?
王牌
Ace.
他的武功比你厉害多
He much better fighter than you.
废话
Do it!
好吧
All right!
白色魔鬼这件事情已经扯得太远了
This White Devil thing has gone far enough.
没有人
Nobody…
有胆子弄乱
messes…
我的发型
with the "do"
他说 抱歉 白色魔鬼
He said, sorry, White Devil…
他必须宰了你
but he must kill you.
我警告你 我猫一样的身手
I'll have you know I have the reflexes of a cat.
和猫鼬一般的速度
And the speed of a mongoose.
快呀
Throw it!
有种就上呀
I dare you!
欧达 别傻傻站着丢枝矛过来给我
Ouda, don't just stand there. Throw me a spear!
痛死我了 刺到骨头里
It's in the bone! It's in the bone!
刺到骨头里了
It's in the bone!
他说你让他们笑得半死
He says you make him laugh.
你简直像个娘儿们
You are like sissy girl!
娘儿们
sissy girl!
酋长说 你现在是瓦诸图之友
Wachootoo Chief say, "You friend to Wachootoo."
不过若明天日正当中时 史卡戈仍未寻回的话
But if the curse of Shikaka not lifted by tomorrow's sun at top of sky…
他们要血洗瓦察提族而且会砸烂你的大头
Wachootoo kill all Wachati and smash your head on a rock.
太棒了
Super.
保重 再见了
Take care now. Bye-bye then.
保重 再见
Take care, now. Super. Bye-bye, then.
你的腿会痛吗 要我背你吗
Are your legs sore? Want me to carry you?
不需要
That won't be necessary, my friend.
我能忍得住痛
I have a high pain threshold.
我的妈呀
Ah, holy monkey!
停下来干嘛
Ace, why you stopped?
瓦诸图族没有偷走那蝙蝠
The Wachootoo didn't take Shikaka.
嗨 欢迎回来
Hi, welcome back.
你能说出这是什么
What would you say this is?
这是瓦诸图巫师的毒箭
Dart of Wachootoo shaman.
没错 和我第一次中的毒箭
Precisely. And when compared to one of the darts…
- 来比较 - 一模一样
- that hit me before? - Same.
你这笨蛋当然看不出来
Only to the untrained eye.
瓦诸毒液来自含羞草系植物
The Wachootoo dart is made of wood from a mimosa tree…
而这个是红蕈系植物毒液
while the other is carved from a red fungus-bearing acalla.
丛林区只有一处有
And there's only one area of the jungle with red…
红蕈类植物
fungus-bearing acallas.
你快回村子通知他们
Go back to the village.
瓦诸图族正午时会发动攻击
Tell them the Wachootoo attack tomorrow at noon.
好的
Okay.
事情快水落石出
This little hound dog just picked up a scent.
就快好了
Won't be long now, Katie.
今晚是个大日子
Big night tonight.
你马上会见到你的新主人
You're going to meet your new owner.
高兴吧 恶心的鼠辈
Good day. Disgusting rat!
看来事情易如反掌
Gravy!
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
- 什么 - 银背猩猩
- What is it? - Silverback.
是只母的
Female.
- 而且很大 - 是吗
- Big. - Yeah?
约在两百码外
About 200 meters…
在我们南方
south.
一只大约值美金五千元
We'd get $5000 for one of those.
- 这只鼠辈怎么办 - 别担心
- What about the rat? - Don't worry about it.
我们会马上回来
We'll be back in no time.
别让它注意到我们
Stay downwind of it.
你这傢伙比我想像还要丑
You're even uglier than I thought.
它可算是庞然大物
She's a big one, isn't she?
这下惨了
Oh, boy.
河畔杨柳青青
Deciduous trees on the bank.
风光无限美妙
Suman shrubs with extreme protococcus.
加上湍湍急流
Steadily increasing water current.
史派克
Spike…
我们可能会越来越惨
I think we could assume the stream gets pretty rough up ahead.
我先替你松绑 你再替我咬断
As soon as I get you loose, you can chew through my ropes.
干得好 加油
That's it! That's it!
加油 该你了
Yes. Your turn.
太好了
All right!
史派克
Spike…
Spike!
我没有死
I'm alive!
投降吧 快投降吧
Say "uncle"! Say "uncle"!
别跑没种就别惹我
Don't start what you can't finish!
认输吧 认输吧
Quit hitting yourself!
河水味道不赖嘛
Oh, water tastes good, yes! Glub, glub.
还是想不通
This isn't over yet.
一定有什么疏忽线索 动机 一定漏掉了什么
There's something I missed. Some clue or motive I've overlooked.
关于动机嘛 应该是
And that motive is…
不知
plah!
快用力想
Think!
有人故意挑起战端
Someone wants the tribes to destroy each other.
两族杀伐 以便渔翁得利
There must be something valuable in this equation.
我看我得进行冥想
Perhaps we should meditate, Spike.
古有名训 定而后能安
For it is said that when seeking answers, one must…
安而复能虑 虑而后能得
quiet the soul in order to hear them.
瓦察提族中之物
What is it the Wachati possess…
除了公主那对大咪咪外
that is of great value to other men…
还有什么会使人垂涎的呢
besides the princess with the amazing rack?
好吧
Alrighty then.
哦
Oh.
王牌 你回来了
You're back?
万事通 给点小道消息吧
You can dispense with the smallpox, all-knowing one.
事关紧急不容搁 废说少说
I'm here on business, and time is of the essence.
很好
Very well.
想知道什么
What answer do you seek?
瓦察提族中之物
What do the Wachati possess…
何者对文明人类具有重大价值
that is of great value to civilized man?
护身符会引导你找出答案
The medallion will lead you to the answer.
护身符还在你身上吧
You do still have the medallion, don't you?
什么护身符 喔 了解
Medallion? Why, surely.
不过它目前与我
I left it back, uh…
肉身同在
with my body.
少打屁
Your aura…
瞧你心虚的
is weakening.
好啦 我扔在洞穴里面
Okay! I threw it in a cave!
你到底要怎样 难道你没掉过东西吗 圣人
What do you want from me? What are you? Mr. Perfect?
要知道护身符在哪
Where is it?
它大概被
It's probably lying…
丢在一堆
in a big pile of…
排泄物
Guano!
蝙蝠屎
They have guano!
就像
Like…
手套
a glove.
嗨 队长
Hi, Chief!
谢谢你来迎接我
Appreciate your meeting me here.
我们走吧
Let's go kick some…
会给总领事难看
consulate butt.
哈啰 王牌
Hello, Ace.
- 回来领赏吗 - 答错你这变态魔王
- You want your money? - Wrong again, Sweeney Toad.
我来找回那圣物蝙蝠 在哪里
I've come for the sacred bat. Where is it?
你在说什么
Why, whatever can you mean?
排泄物啦
Guano!
阿呆
Hello.
大便 听懂了吗
Does poop ring a bell?
动物排泄物是大自然肥料
Guano mines as a source of nitrate…
占全世界肥料百分之八十四
producing 84 percent of the world's fertilizer…
毎年产值约美金十四亿
a $1.4-Billion industry.
这就是战争起因
That's what this war is about.
由于蝙蝠洞属于瓦察图族让你无法据为己有
You can't take possession of the caves while the Wachati inhabit the area.
而那些大便
And you want that dookie so bad…
让你垂涎三尺
you can taste it.
我以为
I thought that…
没错 谢谢你 老葛
Yes, thank you, Fulton.
你很会编故事 威龙先生
That's a fine theory, Mr. Ventura.
我跟这件事有何牵连
What's it got to do with me?
我还以为你
I thought you'd…
不会问了呢
never ask.
我初见你时注意你鞋上有白点
When I met you, there was a white substance on your shoe.
昨天我发现同样的东西
Yesterday, I saw the same substance outside the hut…
我想到白蝙蝠大便是白色的
and it hit me that the Great White Bat has white guano.
这就是你跌跤的原因
That's what you slipped in! That's what was on your shoe!
你手上的伤就是这么来的
And that explains the abrasion on your palm!
我倒带一遍 仔细看
Let me run that back for you.
你就是这么摔的
That's what you slipped in! That's what was on your shoe!
手上的伤是这么来的
And that explains the abrasion on your palm!
我怎么那么厉害
Damn, I'm good!
你有同感吗
Can you feel that, huh?
是这样吗 阿呆
Can you feel it, Captain Compost?
末日降临了
The day of redemption is at hand!
快忏悔吧
Repent!
信我者得永生
And thou shall be saved.
厉害厉害果然是高手
Very good.
我想这案子被你破解了
I believe you've solved the case.
有件事我倒是还想不通 柏瓦蒂尔先生
One thing I still don't understand, Mr. Belvedere.
若你是卑鄙无耻下流的主谋者
If you are the slime behind this little flim-flam…
为什么 哦 为什么
why, oh, why…
要雇用我办案
did you hire me?
为了日后法律调查时
I'm afraid there'll be an investigation after the war.
你可以替我作证脱罪
You were my alibi…
证明我有尽全力阻止战争发生
to prove I'd done everything I could to stop it.
抓起来
Arrest him.
Arrest him!
请把他抓起来
Please arrest him.
老师说 抓起来
Simon says, "Arrest him."
我还以为任何动物你都喜欢 威龙先生
I thought you loved all animals, Mr. Ventura.
要把他钉在墙上吗
Shall I stick him on the wall?
我看免了 卡吉
Heh, no, I don't think it'll be necessary, Gahjii.
威龙先生盗走了圣物蝙蝠
Mr. Ventura has very cleverly stolen the sacred bat of the Wachati.
很不幸 我们未能及时寻回无法阻止战争发生
Unfortunately, we were unable to recover it in time to stop the war.
把灯关掉
Hit the lights!
开关在你后面
The switch is on the wall beside you! Go for it!
快关上
Flick it!
哦 好耶 我们坐牢吧
Alrighty, then. Shall we go to jail?
你干嘛 黑魔王啊
What are you? H.R. Shove-n-Stuff?
上车
Get in!
等一下
Just one more thing.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
停 快停下来
Stop it! I said, stop it!
象儿 我们搬救兵去
To the jungle, Boba!
战友们
Friends…
各位丛林弟兄们
rodents…quadrupeds.
大家注意
Lend me your ears!
你这白痴 竟然让他给跑了
Imbecile! You let him get away!
你难道对部落屠杀毫不关心
You don't seem to understand. The tribe will be killed.
记得提醒我寄致悼卡
Remind me to send a sympathy card.
那混蛋跑不了的
We're going to get the bastard.
我们现在什么办法也没有
There's nothing he can do now.
蝙蝠在我们手上 又近中午
We've got the bat, and it's nearly noon.
外面怎么一回事
What the hell's going on?
你看
You see…
人与动物如此和谐共存
humans and animals can live in harmony!
哇
Whoa.
王牌 抱歉来迟了
Sorry for the delay, Ace.
嘿 动物大盗
Hey, poachers!
和这臭小子打个招呼
Say hello to my stinky little friend!
走开 走开
Get out! Get out!
没那么简单让你溜掉
Not so fast, Sally!
快拿开啦
Get it away!
这傢伙想甩掉我
Aw, he wants to go off-road.
讨厌啦
Aw.
你都不跟人家玩
Nobody wants to play with me.
笨蛋
Loser!
我们在领事馆见过嘛
From the consulate, right?
真诡异
This is weird.
中午了
Noon.
瓦察提族
The Wachati.
意志力克服心理障碍
The spirit will overcome.
猎头族
Headhunters!
史卡戈来了
Shikaka!
借过 大家让路
Coming through. Clear a path, people!
他俩将在族人面前行周公之礼
They will now consummate the marriage as the tribe watches.
王牌 干得好 你一定感到很骄傲
Well done, Ace. You must be extremely proud.
骄傲徒然令人嫌恶
Pride is an abomination.
修道之人
One must forego the self…
需以无我进行灵修
to attain spiritual creaminess…
方能避免
and avoid the chewy chunks…
自我之堕落
of degradation.
- 他说什么 - 我想他说的是 她不是处女
- What's that he's he saying? - I think he's saying, "She's not a virgin."
他们连这个也看得出来
They can tell that?